# **ERIK KIMSEY**

# // SOFTWARE ENGINEER

# erikkimsey.com

T: 540 278 4525 E: kimseyerik@gmail.com

github.com/erikkimsey linkedin.com/in/erikkimsey

As a creative technologist and software engineer, I find the best tools and architecture for the job. Experimentation and breadth of experience are at my core. I strive for resuability, modularity, and succinctness. My passions lay in building intuitive, performant, innovative, and beautiful technology.

### SKILLS

#### **Full-Stack Engineering**

- · JavaScript, React, NextJS
- Redux
- CSS3 / Sass / CSS-in-JS
- HTML5
- NodeJS / Express
- · Relational & NoSQL DBs
- GraphQL
- Apollo-Server / -Client
- Python / Django
- Webpack
- Test-Driven Development
- Bootstrap 4
- · Web Audio, Web Sensor APIs
- P5.js, D3.js,
- Angular

#### Languages

- Javascript (ES6/7)
- Python
- · SQL
- GraphQL
- · Java (Android)
- Processing
- · C/C++

# **Design Tools**

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- · Adobe InDesign
- Adobe XD

#### Misc. Technology

- React-Native
- Android SDK
- ARCore
- Propellerhead Reason
- Abelton Live
- Audacity
- Blender
- Unity3DJUCE
- · Arduino / IC
- · Adobe Premiere
- Adobe AfterEffects

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 09/2019 - 11/2019 CHATWISE

#### **Software Engineer**

(Node/Express, Postgres, ngrok, & Messenger API)

 Using Messenger API, Postgres, and React, develop a dynamic chatbot that provides Blinkist-type functionality within Messenger.

### 06/2019 - 09/2019

#### THE REALM

#### Software Engineer

#### (React-Native, Redux, ES6, Figma)

 Within React-Native, I contributed to architecting and developing the Realm gamer-focused marketplace and social-media app.

#### 6/2018 - 09/2018 NEXTLEVEL / B612 DESIGN

#### Front-End Engineer

#### (Angular 4, Sass, Bootstrap, & D3)

 Contributed to the development of an interactive guilloche for use by a Stuttgart design firm, B612,

#### 1/2018

#### **RAINCROW**

# **Back-End Engineer**

## (NodeJS & Redis)

Contributed to the early-stage engineering of a Node server and Redis database supporting the activity of a MMORPG (Covens)

#### 10/2016 - 6/2017 CHARTIQ

#### JavaScript Engineer

#### (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, & AngularJS)

- Helped implement "ProCharts" in a ChartIQ client's application
- Contributed to performance upgrades, using JavaScript, to ChartIQ's flagship financial-charting solution

# EDUCATION

#### 2018 - 2019 COMPUTER SCIENCE

Lambda School

#### Curriculum:

- Full-Stack Web Development
- Database and RESTful API Design
- Programming paradigms (Declarative, Imperative, and Procedural)
- Software Design Patterns
- Single-Page Application Development
- · Algorithm Analysis
- Data Structures
- · Theory of Computation
- · Computer Architecture
- Cellular Automata
- Version Control
- Agile (Scrum and Kanban) and Waterfall techniques

# 8/2017 - 12/2017 COMPUTER SCIENCE

#### OSU

- · Object-Oriented Programming in C++
- Discrete Maths

#### 2012

#### **WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT (CERT)**

Blue Ridge Community College

- Javascript, HTML, CSS, Java
- · Graphic Design Concepts
- Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign

#### 2006 - 2010 PHILOSOPHY (BS)

James Madison University

Minors: creative writing & design

- Phi Sigma Tau Philosophy Honors Society Member
- Director of the Club of Creative Writing